Guide to the Democracy and communication technologies conference records, 1990-1991.
Democracy and communication technologies conference records, 1990-1991
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Democracy and communication technologies conference records, 1990-1991.
13-06-2640
Cornell University.
.5 cubic ft.
Program, correspondence, notes, flyers, mailing lists, articles, videotapes, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Program, correspondence, notes, flyers, mailing lists, articles, videotapes, and other materials relating to the conference. Also includes videotapes of most conference sessions. Major topics discussed at the conference included independent video production and political activism, video documentaries, media and communities of color, U.S. media and the Gulf War, progressive computer networks, community radio, and television in Colombia.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Rose K. Goldsen memorial conference was held at Cornell University on Sept. 20-22, 1991.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Program, correspondence, notes, flyers, mailing lists, articles, videotapes, and other materials relating to the conference. Also includes videotapes of most conference sessions and the text of the opening address by Alice H. Cook, "Rose Goldsen: Recollections and Reminders." Major topics discussed at the conference included independent video production and political activism, video documentaries, media and communities of color, U.S. media and the Gulf War, progressive computer networks, community radio, and television in Colombia.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Goldsen, Rose Kohn.
Subjects:
Communication in politics.; Communication--Political aspects.; Communication and culture.; Communication--Social aspects.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Planning Notes (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence - conference planning Dec. 1990-Sept. 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Buildings and rooms (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Cornell Catering (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Hotel information (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Publicity - posters, flyers, invitations (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Publicity - draft notes for flyers; drawings by Peter Kahn, Emily Lyons (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Publicity - notices, public service announcements, press releases, newspaper articles (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Publicity - Latin American Studies mailing list (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Publicity - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence - conference attendees, information requests, personal invitations July-Sept. 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Registration forms received (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Conference programme and registration table information (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Presenters - bios, social security numbers, travel information (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Informational materials and forms for presenters, attendees (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Alice H. Cook, "Rose Goldsen: Recollections and Reminders" (text of opening address Sept. 20, 1991 ) (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Materials distributed at conference by participants (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Conference evaluations (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Azriel Bibliowicz, "Stories from the Amazon by Rose K. Goldsen" (notes and publicity re: presentation Sept. 23, 1991 ) (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Correspondence - follow-up to conference Sept. 1991-Jan. 1992 includes address list of participants (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Conference report - Matthew's evaluation, financial summary (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Alternatives Library articles 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Whole Earth Review articles 1985-1990 on politics of communication technologies (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Media politics - miscellaneous articles (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Deborah Brecher (Women's Computer Literacy Center) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Carlos Cortez (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Deep Dish Television (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Mary Jo Dudley, "Uncovering the Invisible Workers" (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Howard Frederick (Institute for Global Communications) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Richard Fung (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Hallwalls Contemporary Arts Center, Buffalo, NY (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Home Economics Conference, Cornell, Oct. 4-5, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- L.A. Law (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Media Alliance (New York State) (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Native North American Media - US-Canada Directory excerpts (Box 2, Folder 14)
- North African computer networks (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Paper Tiger Television, New York City (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Marcelle Pecot - Media Literacy and Community Outreach project (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Peru - William Foote Whyte, "Rural Peru - Peasants as Activists" (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Squeaky Wheel (Buffalo Media Resources, Inc.) (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Ting-Li Wang, "Collective and Personal Resistance in the Newsprint Media by Women Journalists" (research funded by Goldsen Committee) (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Women and media (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Women in sociology (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Video tapes
  - Master tapes
    - 1 - Alice Cook (27:00); Herbert Schiller (1:27) - Fri., Sept. 20, 1991, 1 (Box 3)
    - 2 - Frank Blythe (32:00); Richard Fung (50:00) - Sat., Sept. 21, 1991, 2 (Box 3)
    - 3 - Philip Mallory Jones (57:00), 3 (Box 3)
    - Azriel Bibliowicz, "Media in Colombia"; Mary Jo Dudley & John Efroymson, "More than the News"; Cathy Scott, "Paper Tiger Television" - Sun., Sept. 22, 1991, 4 (Box 3)
    - Patricia Zimmerman, "Gulf War's Collateral Damage" - Sun., Sept. 22, 1991, 5 (Box 3)
  - Series A
    - 1 - Alice Cook; Herb Schiller - Fri., Sept. 20, 1991, 6 (Box 3)
    - 2 - Billie Jean Isbell (Intro); Frank Blythe; Richard Fung; Philip Jones - Sept. 21, 1991, 7 (Box 3)
    - 3 - Philip Jones (cont.); Ayoka Chenzira; Mary Jo Dudley - Sat., Sept. 21, 1991 [RESTRICTED], 8 (Box 5)
    - 4 - Mary Jo Dudley (cont.); ACS Students; Jeronimo Camposeco; J.K. Langford - Sat., Sept. 21, 1991, 9 (Box 3)
    - 5 - J.K. Langford (cont.); Deborah Brecher; John Efroymson; Squeaky Wheel - Sat., Sept. 21, 1991, 10 (Box 3)
    - 6 - Squeaky Wheel; Gossa Tsegaye - Sat., Sept. 21, 1991 // Azriel Bibliowicz, Sun., Sept. 22, 1991, 11 (Box 3)
    - Cathy Scott; Howard Frederick - Sun., Sept. 22, 1991, 12 (Box 3)
    - Karen Helmerson; John Hochheimer - Sun., Sept. 22, 1991, 13 (Box 4)
  - Series B
    - Sept. 20, 1991 - Alice Cook; Herb Schiller, 14 (Box 4)
    - Sat. Sept. 21, 1991 - 9:00 am - Frank Blythe; 9:45 - Richard Fung, 15 (Box 4)
    - Sat. Sept. 21, 1991 - 11:00 - Philip Mallory Jones; 11:45 - Ayoka Chenzira [RESTRICTED], 16 (Box 5)
    - Sat. Sept. 21, 1991 - 1:45 - Mary Jo Dudley; 2:30 - ACS Video Project; 3:15 - Jeronimo Camposeco, 17 (Box 4)
    - Sat. Sept. 21, 1991 - 4:30 - J.K. Langford; Fadya El-Rayess; 5:15 - Deborah Brecher, 18 (Box 4)
    - Sun. Sept. 22, 1991 - Azriel Bibliowicz; Dudley & Efroymson, "More Than the News", 19 (Box 4)
    - Sun. Sept. 22, 1991 - Cathy Scott, "Paper Tiger Television", 20 (Box 4)
    - Sun. Sept. 22, 1991 - 11:00 am - Patricia Zimmerman (conclusion), 21 (Box 4)
    - Sun. Sept. 22, 1991 - 12:30 pm - Cathy Scott, "Deep Dish TV"; 1:00 - Howard Frederick; 1:30 - Karen Helmerson, 22 (Box 4)
    - Sun. Sept. 22, 1991 - John Hochheimer; Wrap Up (Graham Leggat), 23 (Box 4)